Over the years, I've seen multiple five-digit bounties
awarded for request smuggling bugs.
So naturally, I'd like to find one myself,
but to be honest, I never did anything more
than just trying to get tool like request smuggler.
So to learn how people are actually earning money
with request smuggling,
I extracted all the reports from the internet
and I studied them.
In this video, I will show you
what is the most common root cause of request smuggling
and also what are the potential areas for future research.
Enjoy.
The most common category that I've noticed
was white space characters in content length
or transfer encoding headers.
So we can see big bounties awarded in this category.
For example, this one in Apple,
a quick recap of what request smuggling even is.
You have a few different ways to tell the server
what is the length of your request.
The most common that we see when we send requests
from the browser is the content length header,
which just tells the server how long our request is.
But there's also transfer encoding chunk header,
which sort of tells the length of the next chunk
and then until it meets zero,
it means there are more chunks to be sent.
And the thing is,
even though we don't see it sent from the browsers,
usually this has the priority over the content length header
and most of request smuggling bugs occur
because one of the component,
either the front end or the back end,
incorrectly interprets these requests
and either prioritizes them incorrectly
or doesn't see one of these headers.
So this category white space characters in CL or TE headers,
it means to obstruct one of these headers,
usually transfer encoding from one of the components.
And I've seen everything.
I've seen spaces starts before the header,
before the colon, after the colon, after the value,
just everything.
In this case,
we have the new line just after the header name,
transfer encoding.
It actually, and then we have the space here,
which is quite important
because it looks like a invalid HTTP request.
Like there's a header name with no column here
and here the line starts with a space.
It looks like an invalid line,
but it actually is a multi-line header
because when the header line starts with a space,
it means that what follows
is the continuation of the previous header.
I don't know if the specification allows the colon
to be in the new line,
but if you would have, for example,
transfer encoding colon chunked,
and then in the next line you would have chunked again,
it would be a valid continuation of the value.
So this bug makes a lot of sense
and just one of the components
bit treated this differently than the other component,
which led to request smuggling here in Apple,
for which there was $36,000 of reward.
So quite a great bug.
And as I told you,
I've seen many different variations
of different new line characters, tabs, spaces,
0x09, 0x07, null bytes inside header.
There was just all the different variations.
There was a total of 26 requests like this.
Then the second group
is just incorrect prioritization of CL and TE headers.
And you could actually argue
that every single of these reports
or almost all of these reports
are incorrect prioritization of these headers.
That's such a hard word.
But in most of these reports like here,
the priorities were straight in all components.
I assume all components
would prioritize transfer encoding
over the content length header.
Just one component did not see this as a valid header.
And in these 13 reports that I have here,
there was just invalid order
just when there was both transfer encoding
and content length header,
the content length would get the priority,
which is not what the specification says.
So it is bad.
A lot of these reports are from the sort of some time ago
for like here, 2019, this is where the original article,
well, not the original,
the article by James Kettle
about HTTP desync being reborn was published.
And some of these reports
where you just send both headers,
the server prioritizes the incorrect one
and that's the bug.
And most newer request smuggling bugs
that I've seen required something more
like required either the obfuscation
by those white space characters
that I've shown you before or something else.
We'll go to the next group,
which is multiple transfer encoding
or CTLs or transfer encoding or content length headers.
Here, for example, we have a request like this
with one content length
and two transfer encoding headers.
Just one of the transfer encoding is invalid.
So I assume what happens is
one component only takes the last value
of transfer encoding sees that it is invalid.
So it instead decides to use the content length header
and the other component sees
either just takes the first value of the header
when there are multiple headers with the same name
or maybe combine these values together.
But one way or another,
it does see the transfer encoding header
and the component that sees
that the chunk transfer encoding sees the request end here
and sees this being the next request.
And then this victims request,
which can be a random request from another user
is like the continuation of this request
while the other component sees this header,
I assume 69 ends somewhere here
and just sees this as the next header as it expects.
So this is what caused this bug.
We only had seven of these,
but that's what caused them.
And before you ask me if I can share all these reports,
I am always sharing these reports in BBRE Premium Archive.
The article is generally for BBRE Premium subscribers
for the members.
And the free video is usually based
on about one third of the case study
and the database is also in the paid version.
And that's where you can find it
is the first link in the description.
The next category that I have is ignoring
the TE or CL headers.
And we can see from seven reports
that I have in this category,
four are from James Kell's article.
The thing is I try to extract separate reports
from his articles to sort of get,
especially when the exploitation
was actually a bit different,
but often he wouldn't mention the bounty.
So I don't know the bounties for this.
I only have one bug with the bounty in this category.
What does it mean to ignore the content length header?
The thing is it's the newer research,
the browser powered desync attacks.
So some endpoints would just ignore
the content length header, even if you send it.
So it doesn't matter if the content length is zero
or if it has an actual value with it.
The server would just not look at this value.
So here we have the case where we use
the content length of 311 in this case.
So this whole second request should be
the body of the first request,
but the server, because it just redirect,
it doesn't actually need the body,
but it should still consume it.
But it ignores it.
And that's why it just sees two different requests
and issues two different responses.
And the great thing about this variation
of request smuggling or desync
is that you can send these two perfectly valid requests
or to be more precise,
this one big request with this as a body.
You can send this from the browser,
which allows client-side attacks,
which allows to attack the victim inside the browser.
And this is a great bug.
And I think usually you're able to achieve the XSS with this
because you can, as you can see,
you can just, in this case,
you can just issue a request to attackers URL,
because we can see that we have Azure victim
and Azure attacker.
So a different host serving the XSS,
but the browser doesn't know it's a different host.
The browser just thinks it's a one request
with the response,
one response where these are the headers
and this is the body.
So a great research and a great, great bugs as well.
Then for request, we have not closing the connection,
which I have the example here.
The thing is when you send something invalid
and the server denies it,
it should also close the connection
to sort of not allow you to send more data.
So if you send a request that's too large,
if you send an invalid header,
if you do things like this
and the server decides it's a bad request,
it should close the connection
because when it doesn't,
it leads to strange things happening.
Like here, we actually have this article
has like five different bugs,
but this particular one,
you just send a request that's too large.
The server replies that it's an invalid HTTP request,
but it keeps the connection open.
And what follows,
so you send the exact value of bytes
that makes the request too large.
And straight after that,
it will consider the next thing, a new request,
previous request was not finished.
So you can just sort of continue talking to the server,
even though you send a request that was too large,
which, yeah, it led to four bugs,
these behaviors not closing the connection.
So it is something to watch out for.
Then I have as well four bugs in the HTTP2 version.
Again, three of those come from the article
by James Kettle.
And I was also sort of wondering,
I'm still wondering what's the reason
that sort of this great research
does not lead to a lot of other bugs being found,
or at least other bugs being published
because maybe people are making a ton of money on this
and they are not publishing it.
But yeah, it's strange.
There's a great research.
There are great bugs.
And then there is nothing.
And I wonder what happens.
These bugs, this is another article.
This one is from 21, 2021.
And what happened here was the downgrading
from HTTP2 to HTTP1.
So the server would use HTTP2 when talking with the client,
but then when the front end would talk with the backend,
it would use HTTP1 again.
And normally it's not a problem,
but it becomes the problem when like here,
it also forwards a very important header
like content length without checking
if it's a valid one or not.
So you sent, this is a sort of HTTP2 syntax
because in HTTP2, the content length header
is not really used because it's a binary protocol
and it doesn't use this to decide
where does the request finish.
So you just send this as a body,
but then when front end would be talking with the backend,
with HTTP1, it does need the content length header
or the transfer encoding chunk, doesn't matter.
And then it just uses the content length
sent by the client without verifying it.
So the backend would think the request ends here
and this is a new request, which is of course not true.
And this led to request smuggling.
We had 20K Netflix, 10K Verizon, 7K Verizon,
seven and a half K Basecamp and surely more bounties
just by James Hell
because he doesn't disclose all the bugs
that he's discovered.
And I wonder what other ones are out there.
Then we have fun ones with Node doing fun stuff.
I have three reports in the only using new line
or carriage return characters as a line terminator.
There were a few fun reports with Node doing strange stuff.
In this case, Node decided...
So in generally, HTTP1 relies heavily on text parsing
and on new lines because it separates different headers
in the body and the end of the request
using where the new lines are.
And the new line is actually two characters,
usually carriage return and line feed.
So, and this is very important,
but Node for some reason decided it's enough
if you just have the carriage return,
which is usually denoted as backslash R or percent zero D.
And here, no other server would consider this
being a new line, but Node did.
And it did consider this to be a valid
transfer encoding chunked header,
which of course is exactly what you need
to desync the backend with the frontend.
And these were reported $1,800
from the internet bug bounty.
The other one is quite similar as well,
but we'll go to the next category
where the server would treat
not a literal chunked transfer encoding
as chunk transfer encoding.
For example, this is a fun one.
I did publish a video.
I will link it in the description
about this request smuggling back with the AJP protocol.
It was a CTF task with the CVE.
And the thing was the code was just only looking
specifically for the chunked transfer encoding chunk
and nothing else would work.
But the other component or the other piece of code
of the same component would treat a value
like transfer encoding chunked chunked
or chunked comma chunked
as a valid transfer encoding chunked header,
which was also enough to desync the server.
And it was a fun exploiting this one.
It was quite hard because the AJP protocol
is something you probably don't know about,
but it was very, very fun.
The next group, CRLF injection,
also three bugs in this category.
And here it's something a bit different
because it's not like most of the other reports
where you sort of send the transfer encoding
and content length header
and one component sees different things than another.
In this case, you just send one request,
but the front end when forwarding the request
messes up with the decoding of this request
and actually makes it like it's two different requests,
which leads to request smuggling as well.
I'm actually surprised this is not more common,
especially I published an article about a great talk
about this bug and I'm quite surprised
how easy it is to misconfigure Nginx to make this possible.
And I'm quite surprised this is not more common
because of this, but I only saw three reports of this.
This particular one was rewarded 12 and a half thousand
dollars.
Now we go into something that I think
is a great area for research.
And it's something I didn't know about
before doing this case study.
There is a thing called trailer,
which means when you have a chunked encoding,
so it's this, so you have the one chunk of length five here,
the other chunk of length two here.
Don't be mistaken, there's no space here in this,
like in here, in the beginning,
I thought it's the leading space type of bug,
but it looks like this because of the line number here,
which I think shouldn't be like this,
but it is not the case, there's no space here.
And the trailer of HTTP request just means
when you have the chunked body encoding,
you can still have some headers after or trailer headers.
I'm not sure if they are treated exactly like
normal headers, I think they shouldn't.
So I did, of course, I've never seen this being used
by an actual application.
And I also didn't see this in any other bug
apart from these two ones.
Both these reports were $4,600, it's a bug in Apache.
And I'm 100% sure this is such a niche feature of HTTP
that it is a good area for research
because there is no way that all the other servers
consume this trailer correctly because of how rare it is.
Then the next category is H2C upgrade.
I've only saw two reports of this in one blog
posted by AssetNode, which is always a great thing.
I also saw this in a CTF task and it looked,
it's not that hard to misconfigure your server
to be able to do this.
But we didn't see more of this in the wild.
The thing is, you can do the upgrade of the HTTP one
to HTTP two, the way that you bypass the reverse proxy.
And then, of course, you can bypass the WAF,
you can bypass the access control
that's on the sort of middle layer, things like this.
So it's a fun bug.
I've tried it a few times.
There is a tool H2C smuggler on GitHub, which does this.
Unfortunately, I haven't found this bug,
but it looks like something that's not,
the attack scenario is quite reasonable.
So I'm sure it's always worth checking for this
when you're testing a target and when this is useful.
And then we have two last categories
with only one bug each.
Here's another fun one with Node doing strange stuff.
Namely, it would replace the carriage return.
So as I said, a new line is usually
carriage return line feed characters.
And for some reason, Node would replace the carriage return
with the dash, which seems weird to me.
I don't know why they did this,
but this is crucial because the content length header
normally contains the dash between the word content
and the word length.
So we should send a request like this.
I think it actually should be denied
because I don't think this character
is allowed in the header name, but it doesn't matter.
But one way or another,
a component that would see this and accept this
would definitely not consider this
being a valid content length header,
but then Node would sort of decode the CR to a hyphen,
which would make this a valid content length header.
So the front end would see these as two different requests.
The back end would see this as one request
with the body length of 42, which I assume is up to here.
So this would be a new request.
So quite a fun one.
I don't know why Node does this stuff,
but Node was definitely something that was fun
during this case study to see the bug like this.
It was only rewarded $500 by the internet bug bounty,
but it's still a fun bug.
And the last category,
which I also think is a good area for some research
is chunk extensions,
which I also up to recently, I didn't know about.
I just learned, I think it was the motivation for me
to do this case study.
I saw a talk about these bugs,
the HTTP garden tool for testing different HTTP servers.
And I learned what a chunk extension is.
And I think this pushed me to do this case study.
So when you have the chunk transfer encoding,
which is this, you can also have chunk extensions.
So after the column, you can have some parameters here
that obviously probably no one in the whole world ever uses,
but that's exactly what we as security professionals,
we want to have a feature that nobody knows about,
but HTTP libraries and servers have to support.
So here there was also some case
where a new line character in the chunk
shouldn't be accepted, but can be accepted.
And it led to do some bugs.
Also a fun one, also a good, great area for research,
because again, this feature is not used a lot.
So maybe this is something
that not all the servers get right.
So if you're looking for areas for further research,
I would definitely look at trailer parsing
and chunk extensions.
They look like very good candidates for bugs to me.
That's it for this video.
Remember that the full case study
is in the BBRE Premium Archive,
but if you want to watch another free case study video,
check out this playlist
because I've already published nine of them.
For now, thank you for watching and goodbye.